<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-23T07:35:42+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hema Priya Dharshini</title><subtitle>My personal website built using jekyll with my own theme</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Needed Time Complexity for programmers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/time-complexity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Needed Time Complexity for programmers" /><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/time-complexity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/time-complexity/">&lt;h4&gt;TIME COMPLEXITY TO BE KNOWN BY PROGRAMMERS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the time when I am preparing for my placements on data structures and algorithms. I have come to understand the importance and need of time complexity for programming. All online coding platforms accept the code only if the code is optimised with the given time and space complexity. The time complexity plays an important role equivalent to programming logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;b&gt;TIME COMPLEXITY&lt;/b&gt; is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, the time complexity is the computational complexity that describes the amount of time it takes to run an algorithm. Time complexity is commonly estimated by counting the number of elementary operations performed by the algorithm, supposing that each elementary operation takes a fixed amount of time to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big-O notation is used to classify algorithms according to how their running time or space requirements grow as the input size (n) grows. This notation characterizes functions according to their growth rates: different functions with the same growth rate may be represented using the same O notation.These are the most common time complexities expressed using the Big-O notation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bigo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find all these implementations using python in the Github repo of&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hemahpd/python_bigo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.😃&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hema</name></author><summary type="html">TIME COMPLEXITY TO BE KNOWN BY PROGRAMMERS It is the time when I am preparing for my placements on data structures and algorithms. I have come to understand the importance and need of time complexity for programming. All online coding platforms accept the code only if the code is optimised with the given time and space complexity. The time complexity plays an important role equivalent to programming logic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blog Zero - Making of this website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Zero - Making of this website" /><published>2020-07-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/first-post/">&lt;h4&gt;MAKING OF THIS WEBSITE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating this website was a journey of trial and error, and experiential guessing. There are so many ways to go about creating a website now and its very easy to get lost in trying to pick the BEST option. As a beginner, I wanted to pick a platform or technology that I could get up and running relatively quickly, so I chose Jekyll, a static website generator for now as it had the possibility of foregoing a database,saving time and effort on the set up and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous website was setup with a Django backend but I didn't host it as I couldn't get the best out of it and was about to learn more about it. You can find the code for that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hemahpd/personal-website-django&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website of mine is &lt;del&gt;probably&lt;/del&gt; definitely overkill for a simple personal website, however it was a good opportunity to learn Jekyll in creating a personal website along with blog.At some point in the future I wanted to move my content to a dynamic website and retain control of how to setup the backend and take the opportunity to learn relevant industry skills. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.😃&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hema</name></author><summary type="html">MAKING OF THIS WEBSITE Creating this website was a journey of trial and error, and experiential guessing. There are so many ways to go about creating a website now and its very easy to get lost in trying to pick the BEST option. As a beginner, I wanted to pick a platform or technology that I could get up and running relatively quickly, so I chose Jekyll, a static website generator for now as it had the possibility of foregoing a database,saving time and effort on the set up and configuration.</summary></entry></feed>